MICHAEL SEOKYOUNG HAN

seokyoung.han@louisville.edu/ +1 202-843-2041 https://kr.linkedin.com/in/michaelshan1 Louisville, KY, 40217

HIGHLIGHT

A highly multidisciplinary Ph.D. candidate with a strong background in Mechanical Engineering, specializing in robotics. Have a comprehensive understanding of the overall development process with over 7 years of diverse experience in designing and implementing robotic systems. Eager to take on new challenges and explore innovative concepts making the world better tomorrow.

EDUCATION

Ph.D.	Candidate	in	Mechanical	Engine	ering

University of Louisville, Louisville, KY, USA

Jan. 2021 - Spring 2024(Exp)

Research Focus : Soft robotics, Biomimetic system development, Kinematics and dynamics, Human-robot interaction

M.S. in Mechatronics

Gwangju Institute of Science and Technology(GIST), Gwangju, Korea

Aug. 2015

Research Focus: Control systems, Robotics

Thesis Title : Development of a Tensegrity Robot and Feedforward Control via Iterative Learning Control Algorithm

B.S. in Mechanical and Automotive Engineering

Kookmin University, Seoul, Korea

Aug. 2013

AWARDS AND HONORS

Winner Prize, Hackerthon Pitch Competition, \$1500, Humana Foundation, USA	2023	
Application for providing correlation between dog's behavior and heart rate		
NSF LaunchIt I-Corp Innovation Award, \$1600, NSF, USA	2023	
Smart device for dogs		
Graduate Student Travel Award, University of Louisville, USA	2023, 2021	
IEEE ROBOSOFT, MRS(Materials Research Society) meetings		
Winner Prize, Mechatronics Capstone Project, GIST, Korea	2014	
Anti-collision system for automobile doors		
Winner Prize, International Micro-Robot Competition, Japan		
Scholarship, Autonomous Vehicle Robot Competition, \$1500, Samsung, Korea		
Grade Scholarship Award, Kookmin University, Korea		

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Ph.D. Candidate, Research Assistant University of Louisville, KY, USA Jan. 2021 - Present Funded by NSF

Advisor: Dr. Cindy K. Harnett(cindy.harnett@louisville.edu)

- Devised **soft tactile sensor**, which can detect lateral as well as normal force
- Designed adaptive grasping controller with an own-developed soft, optical tactile sensor
- Constructing highly-anthropomorphic robotic finger system

Robotics R&D Engineer

Aug. 2016 - Apr. 2019

University of Texas Health Science Center(UTHealth), Houston

Spun-off ColubrisMX.Inc

Supervisor: Dr. Dongsuk Sin(donnie.shin@colubrismx.com)

Currently EndoQuest Robotics

- Constructed an automated calibration system based on a learning control method for verification surgical apparatuses assembly.
- Developed control strategies for **tendon-driven minimally invasive surgical robot** systems. Especially, kinematics of the articulated robot structures and motion validation were the main focus.
- Researched how to bridge a gap between the system model and real hardware to make high accuracy
 motion, which has to do with controlling undesirable movement of robot such as hysteresis, friction,
 etc.

Research Associate Aug. 2015 - Jul. 2016

Gwangju Institute of Science and Technology(GIST) Funded by Korea Atomic Energy Research Institute Advisor: Dr. Hyosung Ahn(hyosung@gist.ac.kr)

- Conducted research to identify dynamics of a **tensegrity robot** to maintain its stable posture and make consistent locomotion
- Designed iterative learning controller generating improved movement after repetitive motion study

Research Intern

Jan. 2012 - Aug. 2013

Kookmin University

• Led an undergraduate team developing an autonomous vehicle robot(sensor fusion, SLAM algorithm)

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Articles

- 1. (Under review) Michael S. Han, Cindy K. Harnett, "Journey from Human Hands to Robot Hands", Bioinspiration & Biomimetics, 2023
- 2. Michael S. Han, Cindy K. Harnett, "Soft, All-Polymer Optoelectronic Tactile Sensor for Stick-Slip Detection", Advanced Materials Technologies, 2022
- 3. Yoon, S., Cheon, S.Y., Park, S., Lee, D., Lee, Y., Han, S., Kim, M. and Koo, H., "Recent advances in optical imaging through deep tissue: imaging probes and techniques", Biomaterials Research, 2022
- 4. S. Jin, S. Han, "Gain optimization of kinematic control for wire-driven surgical robot with layered joint structure considering actuation velocity bound", The Journal of Korea Robotics Society, 2020
- 5. S. Jin, S. Lee, J. Lee, S. Han, "Kinematic Model and Real-Time Path Generator for a Wire-Driven Surgical Robot Arm with Articulated Joint Structure", Applied Sciences, 2019

Peer-Reviewed Conference Publications

- 1. (Under review) Michael S. Han, J-T. Lin, Cindy K. Harnett, "A Bio-Inspired Robotic Finger Driven and Shape-Sensed by Soft Optical Tendons", RoboSoft IEEE, 2024, San Diego
- 2. (Under review) Paul Bupe, Jr., Yuhao Jiang, J-T. Lin, Tram Nguyen, Michael S. Han, Daniel M. Aukes, C. K. Harnett, "Embedded Optical Waveguide Sensors for Dynamic Behavior Monitoring in Twisted-Beam Structures", RoboSoft IEEE, 2024, San Diego
- 3. Christopher J. Kimmer, Michael S. Han, Cindy K. Harnett, "Strained Elastic Surfaces with Adjustable-Modulus Edges (SESAMEs) for Soft Robotic Actuation", ICRA IEEE, 2023, London
- 4. **Michael S. Han**, Dan O. Popa, Cindy K. Harnett, "Anti-Slipping Adaptive Grasping Control with a Novel Optoelectronic Soft Sensor", RoboSoft IEEE, 2023, Singapore
- 5. S. Han, K. Jeong, H. Ahn, "Iterative Learning Control for Trajectory Tracking of Tensegrity Robot", Control Automation Robotics & Vision on IEEE, 2014

Conference Extended Abstracts and Posters

1. **Michael S. Han**, "Measurement of Lateral Force and Slipping Based on Optical Fiber Mechanism", Materials Research Society, 2021 Fall

Patents

- 1. (pending) Michael S. Han, Cindy K. Harnett, "Optoelectronic Soft Tactile Sensor for a Stick-Slip Control", US Patent Application No.18/220,443, Filed Jul. 2023
- 2. S. Han, T. JANG, D. Kim, H. KIM, J. LEE, K. Nam, Y. Park, D. Shin, "End effector and end effector drive apparatus", AU2020210173B2, application date Jun. 2017
- 3. T. JANG, D. Kim, H. KIM, J. LEE, K. Nam, Y. Park, D. Shin, S. Han, "Surgical apparatus", EP3799822A1, application date Dec. 2017

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Matlab, Simulink, Python, NI Labview, Solidworks, 3D Printing, Comsol, C/C++, ROS, Zemax